# Anika Tahsin Chowdhury Simi

<u>anikachy4@gmail.com</u> | <u>linkedin: //www.linkedin.com/in/anika-tahsin-chowdhury/</u> | Dublin, Ireland(Eligible to work full-time(Stamp 1G)) | +353 89 4324861

## **SUMMARY**

I have developed a deep understanding of Algorithms and Data Structures and have received recognition for my performance in several national Programming Contests. Throughout my professional career, I have gained experience in iOS development, making contributions to Samsung's iOS applications like Samsung Galaxy Wearable, Samsung Galaxy-Buds, and SmartThings. My enthusiasm lies in adopting new technologies and creating creative solutions for challenging issues. My skill set includes expertise in C++, Swift Software Development Life Cycle, Git, Algorithm design and Data Structure, and familiarity with various Design Patterns and Principles such as MVVM, SOLID, MVC, and others.

## **TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES**

- **Programming Languages:** C/C++, Swift, Familiar with JavaScript, HTML, CSS(Working knowledge).
- Technology: iOS Application Development, Xcode, Git, Agile Scrum.
- Additional skills: Problem Solving, Algorithms and Data Structures.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Research Assistant**

## **University College Dublin**

Aug 2023 — Nov 2023

 Contributing to develop a web-application using internal technologies, which will be the protfolio of HOLOS-IE(a digital Platform which will offer a critical opportunity for Ireland to address climate change challenges and environmental degradation)

### **Software Engineer**

# Samsung R&D Institute Bangladesh

Apr 2019 — Aug 2022

- Contributed to the development and improvement of the Samsung SmartThings Scan Nearby feature, resulting in increased user satisfaction and onboarding efficiency.
- Developed Backend Driven UI with RESTful API integration and implemented new features of UI Screens for the Samsung Galaxy Wearable, which includes the ability to connect to mobile devices and facilitate data backup and restoration using Samsung Account.
- Developed new-feature of Samsung Galaxy Buds, such as Equalizer
- Adhered to Test-Driven Development practices to increase code stablity and making less bug .
- Improved and fixed bugs in the SmartThings Help Card, enhancing the user experience.
- Successfully applied refactoring techniques to significantly reduce the Cyclomatic and Cognitive Complexity of the SmartThings codebase, resulting in improved code quality and maintainability.
- Demonstrated strong independent problem-solving skills by developing UI and Utility modules and writing
  Unit tests for the Samsung Galaxy Wearable and SmartThings projects.

# **PROJECTS**

- <u>iBooks</u>: iBooks is Developed using Swift in Xcode. The app is to showcase of Backend-Driven UI implementation, used mock-server to fetch book list and details, with handling exception occurences.
- Noughts and Crosses: Designed and developed an Android Noughts and Crosses game using Java and Android SDK. Implemented a fixed-depth minimax artificial intelligence algorithm to enable single-player mode, allowing players to compete against a computer opponent.

### **EDUCATION**

## Leading University, Sylhet, Bangladesh

Oct 2016 — Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science and Engineering

## **Sylhet International University**

Apr 2014 — Oct 2016

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science and Engineering

### **AWARDS**

328th place at Google Code Jam to I/O for Women, Google

Aug 2018

10th Place at DIU National Girls Programming Contest, Daffodil International University

Aug 2017

9th - NSU IUGPC 2018, North South University

Apr 2018

23rd LU National ICT Fest Programming Contest, Leading University

Dec 2018